A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Office of the President, Office Files of McGeorge Bundy FA617
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Appendix A: Reports
  - Marks, Lee. Memorandum for the File: BNS - Common Carrier of Cooperative, 1966 September (Report 10944)
  - Martus, Marjorie. The Ford Foundation's Program in School Staff Development 1970 - 1974, 1974 September (Report 2836)
  - Mason, Edward S. The Present Status and Future Prospects of the Investment Planning Project, 1976 January (Report 9409)
  - Meade, Edward J. Jr. Instruction via Electronic Communications Satellite, 1966 July (Report 1134)
  - Meade, Edward J. Jr. Program Opportunities in South Viet-Nam for Foundation Consideration, 1966 (Report 11079)
  - Measham, Anthony. The Foundation and Population, Health, and Nutrition in Bangladesh, 1977 October (Report 10969)
  - Miller, Frank J. Languages and Linguistics. Comments on Agenda Paper, Session V, Representatives' Meeting, Nairobi, 1968 June (Report 10955)
  - Miller, Frank J. [Observations in Jakarta from April 3 to 9, 1966] (Report 11056)
  - Miller, Frank J. Prospects for Program, Budgets and Operations: Pakistan: Bell Memo, 1974 July (Report 9009)
  - Miller, William Lee. At This Point in Time, 1973 October (Report 6560)
  - Miller, William Lee. We Will Substitute a Hum, 1974 March (Report 3498)
  - Moore, Charles F. [Report on F.O.R.D.: Families Opposing Revolutionary Donations], 1970 September (Report 10894)
  - Nielsen, Waldemar. Recommended Program of Foundation Action in the Field of the Mass Media and International Communication (Report 11045)
  - Nelson, Courtney. International Division Organization, 1970 January (Report 10975)
  - Nelson, Gordon. An Overview of Bangladesh Agriculture, 1977 October (Report 10967)
  - Oppenheimer-Nicolau, Siobhan. The Changing Role of Women in U.S. Society, 1972 February (Report 10895)
  - Pfanner, David. Forestry Development in South and Southeast Asia, 1966 March (Report 2454)
  - Robinson, Marshall. Economics and the Ford Foundation: Some Background, 1979 January (Report 9111)
  - Robinson, Marshall. Resources and the Environment: An International Agenda, 1974 September (Report 10980)
  - Ruff, Larry E. Progress Report on Development of a Nuclear Analysis Program, 1975 March (Report 10896)
  - Ruof, Peter. Free University, Berlin - Your Lunch with President Kreibich, 1975 (Report 11064)
  - Ruof, Peter. Glazer-Moynihan Proposal on Race and Ethnicity, 1974 (Report 11063)
  - Scanlon, John. The Ford Foundation and the Atlantic University Center, 1976 December (Report 9782)
  - Schoettle, Enid C.B. Memorandum of Future Support of Programs for Research and Training in International Security and Arms Control, 1976 (Report 11062)
  - Sharpe, Richard S. Notes taken at March 1, 1978 Officers Meeting Discussion re Constructive Impact of Our Work on Government Policy, 1978 March (Report 10899)
  - Sharpe, Richard S. Program Staff Views on Responsive Budget System Options, [1978?] (Report 10891)
  - Sheldon, Richard C. ACLS Meeting on Scholarly Communication, 1974 (Report 11073)
  - Sheldon, Richard C. Arts Activities and Institutional Framework, 1975 (Report 11074)
  - Smith, Theodore M. Human Rights Discussion: January 19, 1976, 1976 January (Report 8748)
  - Smith, Theodore M. Individual Research and Writing Awards, 1975 (Report 11039)
  - Smock, David R. Briefing Information for Ghana Visit, 1970 March (Report 10959)
  - Smock, David R. Evaluation of IITA Resettlement Project, 1970 March (Report 10958)
  - Smuckler, Ralph H. Population. Comment on Agenda Paper. Kenya Meeting of Representatives, 1968 June (Report 9478)
  - Staples, Eugene S. Budget Review, 1970 January (Report 8927)
  - Staples, Eugene S. [India Visit], 1971 (Report 11055)
  - Staples, Eugene S. A Note on Southeast Asia: Vietnam and the Philippines, 1973 March (Report 9093)
  - Staples, Eugene S. A Report on Our Thinking about East Asia, 1970 January (Report 5009)
  - Stone, John R. Ford Foundation Stock Proxy Voting Procedures and Record, 1972 (Report 11020)
  - Stone, John R. Ford Foundation Stock Proxy Voting Procedures and Record, 1972 (Report 11021)
  - Sucherman, Stuart F. Task Force on Telecommunications: Status Report, 1973 April (Report 10800)
  - Sutton, Francis X. Congress for Cultural Freedom, 1967 September (Report 2784)
  - Sutton, Francis X. Cultural Implications of Aid Programs, 1970 May (Report 3152)
  - Sutton, Francis X. The International Legal Center, 1971 (Report 11068)
  - Sutton, Francis X. Interviews with Overseas Staff in Latin America, 1972 May (Report 10942)
  - Sutton, Francis X. Refugees, 1979 February (Report 10037)
  - Sutton, Francis X. Report on the Foundation's Activities Relating to Europe and Canada in the Fiscal Year 1970, 1970 December (Report 10990)
  - Svala,Trudy. Family Planning Programs in the Soviet Union and Communist China, 1970 November (Report 10987)
  - Sviridoff, Mitchell. Division of National Affairs: Budget Planning Paper, FY 1974-75, 1973 February (Report 10978)
  - Sviridoff, Mitchell. New or Expanded Program Ideas for National Affairs' Planning Agenda, 1972 February (Report 2460)
  - Sviridoff, Mitchell. San Francisco State College Strike - Mediation Efforts Supported by the Ford Foundation, 1969 (Report 11077)
  - Sviridoff, Mitchell. Summary of FY 1973 Budget, 1973 February (Report 10977)
  - Sviridoff, Mitchell. The Working Class Program: A Review Memorandum for Discussion, 1975 June (Report 10981)
  - Towers, Perrin, Forster. Report on Funding for Retiree Group Insurance Benefits, 1979 March (Report 10991)
  - Trottenberg, Arthur D. Custody and Registration of Foundation Securities, 1974 (Report 11037)
  - Trottenberg, Arthur D. Executive Officers' Termination Benefits, 1979 January (Report 10933)
  - Trottenberg, Arthur D. The Ford Foundation as an Affirmative Action Employer, 1973 (Report 8011)
  - Trottenberg, Arthur D. Items, Issues, Ideas That Should be Considered for Inclusion on Long Term Foundation Planning Looking Toward Fiscal Year 1974-1975, 1972 February (Report 2457)
  - Trottenberg, Arthur D. Report of the Subcommittee on Information and Management in the Ford Foundation, 1975 June (Report 6593)
  - Trottenberg, Arthur D. Review of Compensation/Fees Paid to Chairmen of the Board and Member-Trustees of Private Foundations, 1976 (Report 11038)
  - Trottenberg, Arthur D. The Role of Women in the Ford Foundation, 1971 June (Report 6316)
  - Trottenberg, Arthur D. Salary Policy for FY 77, 1976 September (Report 10931)
  - Trottenberg, Arthur D. Salary Policy for 1975, 1974 September (Report 10932)
  - Ward, F. Champion. Assistance to Education in the Seventies, 1971 October (Report 3974)
  - Ward, F. Champion. Foundation Experience in Iran and Turkey, 1979 March (Report 8893)
  - Ward, F. Champion. Model of a Foundation Administered Program to Provide Financial Aid Directly to..., 1970 (Report 11066)
  - Ward, F. Champion. The Professor as Educator: Replies to an Inquiry Concerning the Number and Nurture of "Faculty Statesmen", 1967 (Report 20940)
  - Ward, F. Champion. Public Education Program Budget Outline, FY 1970 - FY 1974, 1969 (Report 11065)
  - Wilhelm, Harry E. Future Program Plans for the Office for Latin America and the Caribbean, 1970 January (Report 4655)
  - Wilhelm, Harry E. A Note on India, 1975 September (Report 4925)
  - Winnick, Louis. The Democratic Policy and How it Works, 1976 (Report 2195)
  - Wortman, Sterling. Progress at IITA (Wortman-Hardin Visit), 1970 February (Report 10957)
- Appendix B: Budget and Finance Committee Papers
  - Proposed Budget: Fiscal Year 1970 (Summary, Program-Related Investments, Education and Research, Humanities and the Arts, International Division, National Affairs, Public Broadcasting, Public Education, Management Costs), 1969 (Report -)
  - Strategic Budget Issues for FY 1971 and Beyond, 1970 (Report -)
  - Proposed Budget: FY 1971, 1970 (Report -)
  - Proposed Budget: FY 1971 -- Five Year Financial Projections, 1970 (Report -)
  - Budget Plans and Problems: FY 1972 and 1973, 1971 (Report -)
  - Proposed Budget -- FY 1972, 1971 (Report -)
  - Proposed Budget -- FY 1973, 1972 (Report -)
  - Preliminary Budget Planning for FY 1974 and 1975, 1973 (Report -)
  - Proposed Budget -- FY 1974-1975 (Management Costs), 1973 (Report -)
  - Our Finances and Our Future, 1974 (Report -)
  - Choices Under a Reduced Program Budget, 1974 (Report -)
  - Our Finances and Our Future Revisited, 1974 (Report -)
  - Retrenchment of Management Costs: A Progress Report, 1975 (Report -)
  - Proposed Revision in 1975 Program Budget and Preliminary Presentations (Report -)
  - Proposed Budget -- FY 1976 and 1977, 1975 (Report -)
  - Proposed Budget -- Management Costs FY 1976, 1975 (Report -)
  - FY 1978-79 Budget Planning: Program Alternatives and Options, 1977 (Report -)
  - Proposed Budget: FY 1978 and 1979, 1977 (Report -)
  - Finance Committee Records, 1966 March 14 (Report -)
  - Finance Committee Records, 1966 June 22 (Report -)
  - Finance Committee Records, 1966 September 28 (Report -)
  - Finance Committee Records, 1966 December 8 (Report -)
  - Finance Committee Records, 1971 March 25 (Report -)
  - Finance Committee Records, 1977 December 7 (Report -)
  - Finance Committee Records, 1978 December 6 (Report -)
  - Finance Committee Records, 1978 December 7 (Report -)
- Appendix C: Speeches
  - Bundy, McGeorge. Main Points of Remarks...Before the Foreign Correspondents Club of Japan, 1966 May 10 (Report 18663)
  - Bundy, McGeorge. The Moral and Social Responsibilities of the Trustees of Foundations. Ciba Foundation’s 25th Anniversary Symposium, 1974 June 17 (Report 18740)
  - Bundy, McGeorge. Prepared Comment. Tokyo Philanthropy Symposium, 1975 January 17 (Report 18744)
  - Bundy, McGeorge. Remarks. Stevenson Lecture, Chatham House, London, 1971 November 30 (Report 18719)
  - Bundy, McGeorge. Remarks. International Institute of Tropical Agriculture, 1970 April 21 (Report 3149)
  - Friendly, Fred. Remarks Prepared for Delivery at the Silver Anniversary Banquet of the Northwest Broadcast News Association. Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1973 February 2 (Report 18875)
  - Friendly, Fred. World Without Distance. An Address Prepared for Delivery to the National Association of Educational Broadcasters Convention in Kansas City, Missouri, 1966 October 24 (Report 1139)
  - Howe, Harold. The Forces for Change in Tuition Policies and Student Aid. Remarks at the Annual Meeting of the College Entrance Examination Board, New York City, 1973 October 30 (Report 19076)
  - Howe, Harold. On Bearing Witness. New York Hilton Hotel, Association of College, University and Community Arts Administrators, 1973 December 16 (Report 19128)
  - LeMelle, Wilbert J. The Black Colleges and African Educational Development. The United Negro College Fund's Annual Spring Conference on American Education. Atlanta, Georgia, 1974 March 24 - 26 (Report 19118)
  - Miller, S.M. Credentialism and the Educational System. American Orthopsychiatric Association, Washington, D.C., 1967 March 23 (Report 3850)
  - Stone, Shepard. Inter American Press Association XXI General Assembly. San Diego, CA, 1965 October 13 (Report 10499)
  - Stone, Shepard. The Role of Foundations in Modern Society. Vienna, 1965 November 22 (Report 19206)
  - Ward, F. Champion. The Fabric of Universities, 1968 November 11 (Report 19246)